#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/pspramodh (LinkedIn) pramodhgps.github.io/ (Personal)

## Top Skills

Machine Learning
Python (Programming Language)
R (Programming Language)

### Certifications

Designer Core
Introduction to Big Data

# Pramodh Gowda

Machine Learning Engineer - Currently building No-Code AI platform at @SwayAI | Data Science Grad at Northeastern University.

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

## Summary

I am a Data Science Grad at Northeastern University with a penchant for deriving insights from massive data volumes. My areas of interest include deep learning, spatial analytics, and large-scale data processing.

Prior to this, I worked as a Data-Engineer with analytical skills and experience in building sophisticated data applications for multinational clients. My skillset includes SQL, R, Python, C, AWS, and ETL tools like Alteryx, Informatica and considerable experience in building visually stunning reports utilizing Tableau.

In the future, I intend to utilize statistical skills and knowledge to solve real-world business problems in an efficient manner.

## Experience

Sway Al

Machine Learning Co-op

May 2022 - December 2022 (8 months)

Burlington, Massachusetts, United States

- \* Developed frameworks to train and deploy ML models for the company's no-code Al platform. Worked extensively with Sagemaker SDK, Multi-Model Server(MMS), and torchserve to serve ML models.
- \* Implemented data processing jobs using PySpark and a host of AWS services to improve the company's data engineering platform.
- \* Refactored the codebase to bring modularity and performance enhancements . Wrote unit tests and functional tests to validate operations performed by data engineering and ML pipelines.
- \* Continuously striving to bring software engineering practices to ML product development.

Khoury College of Computer Sciences Graduate Teaching Assistant January 2022 - May 2022 (5 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

DS3500 - Advanced Programming with Data

Deloitte India (Offices of the US)

5 years 11 months

Senior Consultant

May 2021 - August 2021 (4 months)

As a senior employee, I led a team of 4 members in an agile environment and achieved business needs in an efficient manner. Architected an automated Data wrangling solution utilizing AWS Stack of RedShift, Glue, Lambda, Sagemaker, and CodeCommit.

#### Consultant

September 2018 - May 2021 (2 years 9 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Developed CI/CD pipeline to process structured and unstructured data from various data sources. Developed ML models which performed regression and classification analysis using Python packages like numpy, pandas, matplotlib and scikit-learn. Developed visualization solutions using Tableau to help clients analyze their company-wide sales performance intuitively.

Business Technology Analyst
October 2015 - August 2018 (2 years 11 months)

As an entry-level analyst, I worked in traditional ETL technologies like Informatica and was involved in upgrading legacy systems to achieve performance improvement. Achieved a core developer certification in Alteryx (a leading Data Science tool) and developed Data Wrangling solutions for clients from different industries.

## Education

Northeastern University

Master of Science - MS, Data Science · (September 2021 - May 2023)

Sri Jayachamarajendra College of Engineering Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electronics and Communications Engineering · (2011 - 2015)

Sadvidya Composite PU College

Pre-University College, Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Biology · (August 2009 - May 2011)